proceed to our fourth and final case
number 12-23 60 uh cozy versus
credential Insurance Company of America
uh Mr Adams we'll be glad to hear from
you whenever you're ready
sir may I please the court good morning
your honors I um my name is Norris Aden
I'm here representing Beth cozy the
appellant in this matter in what appears
to be the Court's only civil matter of
the day um at least for this panel
uh uh this case is this case presents a
fairly typical factor in Arisa benefit
claims uh excuse my voice I'm having
allergies this week and if I start
coughing I'll grab the water I'm with
you I'm suffering as well um but uh in
this case it's like many other benefit
claims under Arisa we have a claimant
that has a disease or
diseases um there's not really a
question about that these diseases cause
some sort of symptoms pain
fatigue um the plant administrator armed
with a report uh from a reviewer either
a usually a vocational reviewer or
medical reviewer acknowledges the
diagnosis but then uh refuses for
whatever reason to to credit the
diagnosis when determining whether or
not to award disability
benefits
um the the examples I can think of one
for each of vocational would be that
they can still meet the restrictions and
limitations of the job medical would be
that subjective symptoms don't equate
with the object Ive evidence available
and I think we have both of those here
um also typical and most risk of
benefits cases is in this case the
standard of review is an important U
consideration for the court
um if the plan has given itself
discretion and done so adequately um an
abuse of discretion standard of review
applies if it doesn't then the default
denovo standard of review applies
um here miss cozy has two claims a uh
short-term disability claim that was
terminated and a long-term disability
claim that was denied um so there's uh
two potential standards of review that
would be applied one to each
claim um and I want to briefly talk
about each of
those with respect to the short-term
disability claim uh at The District
Court below the parties agre agreed that
uh the claim was not governed by Arisa
the short-term disability claim was not
governed by Arisa such that ordinary
breach of contract principles applied to
it I was a little surprised you didn't
pray a jury trial on that your honor we
actually um didn't get deep that until
matter of fact I argued that it was
narissa all Through summary judge
briefing and it wasn't until summary
judgment briefing closed that credential
filed a brief they they
fought that that argument it wasn't
until after summary judgment brief and
closed that they filed a brief with the
court that
said wait you're right it is not
governed by Rissa my point is and I
don't mean it as criticism but when you
file the
complaint um I guess what I'm I mean in
fact I see a lot of irisa claim claims
Council will often pray a jury trial
just sort of out of an abund
of some might say silliness or some
might say caution you never know what
might happen but anyway I I don't want I
don't want if I had um before the the
administrative record was submitted
during the litigation if I had figured
that out I probably would have but it
was with as well within the litigation
that I did
um uh
so all parties agree that the breach of
contract ordinary North Carolina
principles uh of of contract
construction
apply um and the district court I
thought a couple of reaches in order to
get to where it got which was that an
abuse of discretion standard applied
even when orisa didn't to the term
disability claim what the district court
did was it applied a case from the
seventh circuit that
said if we can look you know even though
risk doesn't apply if we can look to the
four corners of the contract cont and
figure an intent to apply a discretion
we're going to go ahead and do that
anyways even though it's not Aisa so the
court looked at the contract and the
only um well actually the court just
decided without deciding that there was
not an adequate Grant of discretion in
the contract but I think Gallagher
supports that um decision so the court
said I'm going to take it a Step Beyond
having not found discretion within the
contract I'm going to go A Step Beyond
and apply a Risa precedent that says an
actually old Risa precedent now that
says I can look at other documents that
are between the parties that are
associated and I can if I can find
discre there then I can apply it here um
so what the court did was it looked the
administrative Services
agreement based on orisa precedent that
said other documents can be part of the
plan documents and it found
discretionary Authority can I ask you
this
um am I right that somewhere in here
judge Schroeder
said even if Den noo standard of review
applies for me the outcome is exactly
the same he did your honor yes so in
that
light where does that leave us it assume
hypothetically that we agree with you
that for both the shortterm and the
longterm
it's denovo and not abuse of discretion
yes sh where does that leave us in light
of the district courts well your honor I
think I would go I would almost turn
that back at you and say even under an
abuse of discretion standard I think
judge Schroeder's wrong in this case so
certainly under Den noo review just
looking at the evidence that was
presented by both sides I think uh Miss
cozy has a very strong case for both
short long term I I'll I'll accept that
a strong
case but where does that leave us are
you are you asking us and I think I know
the answer to this are you asking us
assuming we agree with you that it's
denovo to rule as a matter of law as
they say in the fifth circuit to
render um of course we got that
pre-existing condition issue floating
around but but I I guess my question is
does does it go back to him go does it
go back to the district
court at least go back to the district
court if we agree with you that it's a
denovo standard
or do we say well the judge has looked
at it PR carefully it's an Arisa case
it's not a jury trial uh he said even if
he applied a d
standard you see what I'm I guess I'm
not asking the question in a very
articulate way I know um I I don't I
think this court can order reinstatement
um I mean it goes back to it goes back
to judge it goes back to the district
court in any event right if we agree
with you yes because because the
pre-existing condition issue needs to be
addressed I mean I think you you agree
with that um I I think that yeah it
certainly was not addressed by the
district court I think the appes would
argue that I think their argument is and
I don't mean to Mr to Carlo he's more
than capable of doing that himself I
think their argument is that this court
can decide it as a first blush I uh in
my briefing tended to disagree with that
um and I do think that probably the
district court has to have the first
shot at that okay as a preliminary
matter on just on pre-existing so would
it would it make sense if we agree with
you I'm just speaking hypothetically
that it's denovo on both shortterm and
long
term are you arguing to
us that that we should send it back for
a
doover under a denovo standard or are
you
arguing don't send it
back please don't send it back I ask you
not to send it back decide it for
yourself because as a matter of law
she's
entitled to benefit we honor I think
that I do think that this court can
order
reinstatement of her of her Ben of her
short-term and Order the order the
district court to order the plan
administrator to give her disability
benefits the pre-existing condition on
the basis that that she's entitled to
benefits as a matter of law as a
substantive matter based on her the
evidence that was presented below and is
in the administrative record that she's
um for example uh the the fact that
vocational reviewer and the medical
reviewer have agreed that travel is a
material on substantial Duty and that
makes this at least a light duty
occupation while their reviewers have
said she can do sedentary at One
reviewer said she can do at least
sedentary but I don't know what that
that doesn't mean she can do light I
mean if I can run three miles it doesn't
mean I can run a marathon so all they
have in the record is that she can do
sedentary but their experts also say
travel's material and substantial and
travel makes this light so as a matter
of law I think the substantive question
of disability can be answered by this
panel that that Beth cozy is entitled to
it um the pre-existing condition is the
only thing that's out there that I don't
that hasn't been decided so I don't know
and that that doesn't apply to short
term correct correct okay and if they're
correct that this court can decide the
pre-existing condition I think there's
no question and maybe it's a matter of
futility to send it back to the district
court because I think there's no
question the pre-existing condition
doesn't apply they can only point to the
short term to
anything it doesn't apply meritoriously
at least because the only doctor's
appointment they can appoint to in the
three months prior to her the three
months that the pre-existing condition
reply the that doctor's
appointment was June 28th J June 25th
2008 and it simply says that Dr Davis
documented that Miss CO's balance was
poor but that her energy level was
improving and documented her Tremor I
don't see that that meets the level of
providing medical treatment care
Consultation
Services to her and if it and even if it
did it would apply to balance not
degenerative dis disease fibromyalgia
um uh chronic fatigue syndrome and so
forth so I don't think that any Merit to
the pre-existing condition argument my
only hesitation is that the district
court judge didn't decide it um but on
the merits of the
disability I think that there's
no no question that my first example the
that the there's the issue of the light
versus sedentary I think there's also a
deer issue here D Perry versus L case
that was decided by this court a couple
years ago wherein as I read
records doctor the reviewing doctors Dr
hes Dr
coell credential in the denial letter
and even the district court all said
look let me give you specific examples
Cole Dr Cole Bell said Cozy's complaints
simply are not borne out through
objective
evaluation has said no objective basis
to support Cozy's occupational impair M
um credential said only self-reported
symptoms um based on these Miss CO's
Physicians have indicated she's unable
to work however the medical data on file
does not support that with objective
evidence and that's the key to the case
right or or one of the keys to the case
is whether there's an absolute
requirement for objective corroboration
I would say that the case can be decided
one setep before that based on the light
versus sedentary
I think this is almost like a fallback
another way Miss cozy wins um because I
I think it's clear by the record that
the doctor and the vocational
reviewer
say travel is material substantial
travel is required you know by the by
this job travel increases it to
something higher than sedentary
vocational reviewer says light and 20
pounds which um I can't travel to Paris
with a 20 lb bag but um it's like the
weight of one shirt for me
um but if you go by what they say it's
at least light and if you go by what
their doctor says Dr ay she's capable of
at least full-time sedentary sustainable
sedentary work she doesn't go further
than that none of the reviewers go
further than sedentary but they all put
a requirement that the travel it's like
saying a um
it's just it bewilders me because the
analysis keeps it seems like it stops
they acknowledge that travel is a
mysterial substantial duty of her job
they acknowledge that that at light and
they acknowledge that the only thing we
have here is telling them it's sedentary
but then they say that's okay I the
analogy that came to my mind is you know
firefighting is sedentary until you go
down the pole you know once you're
fighting a fire you're fighting a fire
and that's a material part of of being a
firefighter if it's a material part of
being a senior marketing manager to
travel internationally and abroad you
know two to eight times a year you can't
dismiss that and say when she's not
traveling at sedentary so I think that
by
itself carries the day is this positive
as a
backup
duperry says if you have objectively
identifiable diagnoses
what she does she has chronic fatigue
she has
fibromyalgia degenerative dis disease
and so forth and if those diseases are
expected to cause the subjective
symptoms that she's complaining about
you can't dismiss them you have to
consider them and here unless the policy
says otherwise and here the policy does
not say otherwise so it's very similar
to dup Perry in that
situation so here we've
got a policy that doesn't prohibit
Reliance on subjective complaints
we've got evidence of her subjective
symptoms we've got evidence that these
diseases do in fact prevent her from
working from her phys Physicians and
herself and her written declarations
from her colleagues we got evidence
from uh her declaration and her family
and colleagues that about the severity
of her
symptoms we've got evidence from R
treating Physicians that these symptoms
are unable to allow to work so when you
combine all that together with a policy
that doesn't reject that you can't
ignore that part of it and that's the
core holding in my view of duperry and
why this is very similar to duperry from
that respect um another issue that I
would draw with the review that's been
given is that there's a substantial
amount of case law that says you have to
consider the combination of
impairments on the person's ability to
function on their work capacity and
there's nowhere in the record where
anyone hired by credential ever looked
at how does a combined with B combined
with C combined with d impact her
ability to function in fact if you look
at Dr A's report it's a
specific report chronic fatigue here's
my conclusion and so forth one after
another broken down into my cusions I
see that my time is up if there are no
other questions I'll sit for rebuttal
you you have some additional time
remaining thank you Mr
Adams good morning morning my name is
Pat D Carlo I represent the defendants U
Miss cozy has no lifting restrictions
whatsoever she has had nothing but
completely normal musculoskeletal exams
uh which have noted full strength and
mobility in all all four um of her
extremities the the the only argument
plaintiff has that she can't travel
because of a lifting restriction is
based on a misreading of Dr A's report
Dr AI does not impose a lifting
restriction he says in his report which
by the way uh was drafted and issued
nine months before the vocational report
came out that he thought she could do
sedentary work and sedentary work was
defined as being able to lift up to 10
pounds it it no time did Dr H suggest
that she had a lifting restriction and
if there is a lifting restriction we
would expect to see that somewhere in
her own medical records and it's not
there uh Miss cozy has had uh
evaluations from gastrologist
endocrinologists cardiologists at least
two neurologists and they've all come up
with either normal findings or or
findings that don't uh explain her
symptoms uh and there there's also
substantial evidence that that Beyond
just the the lack of um evidence of a
cause for a disability or objective
proof for disability Miss cozy has not
always followed the recommendations of
her treating Physicians uh Dr Miller the
gastrologist and and there actually are
two Dr Millers in the case um I'm I'm
referring now to the gastrologist
recommended a small bow x-ray Miss Co
refused that Dr AAR a neurologist
recommended a Rheumatology concert what
is the what is the relevance of all of
this that uh she has not um followed up
with doctors as indicated for uh
treatment that that may uh resolve this
question of of whether she does have a
disabling condition so I I I disagree
with the argument that this is just you
is is objective proof uh required or not
and that's the end of the analysis
objective proof may not be required in
all situations but it's certainly a
relevant factor to consider among other
factors other factors in this case
include not following up with Physicians
she says she's uh disabled as a result
of
M if we are persuaded that the district
court seemed to require as a matter of
law objective
evidence would that be reversible
error I don't believe so because I I
believe the judge looked not only at the
lack of objective but some of the other
factors as well and it's important to
look at all the factors not just one
objective proof may not be dispositive
but it it's certainly relevant to the
question of of whether plff has has
proven uh their burden of proof and and
the Rheumatology is is particularly
important because that's the specialist
who treats fibromyalgia she was referred
to a rheumatologist and and decided not
to and let me ask this the judge
said disc disc um abuse of discretion
standard applies
but even if denovo
applied same result the outcome here
would be the same correct how do you do
that in the context of summary
judgment if
if
if uh Miss Co is entitled to all
inferences under an abuse of discretion
standard and all inferences in her favor
under a de noo
standard I guess I'm trying to work out
in my mind how you how you work that out
on a on the basis of a summary judgment
motion these cases generally are
addressed in the summary judgment
context because we're looking at an
administrative record there may be
arguments about the implications of what
the facts mean but the facts are
essentially not in dispute we disagree
about the conclusions but what the
doctors said at different times is all
documented the record and something that
that the judge here was able to evaluate
but the judge did seem to look awfully
hard and was unable to find objective
evidence correct and so if it's denovo
an objective evidence is not a cqu non
of a disability claim under this policy
I'm just trying to figure out right
right how a judge could say it's it's
abuse of discretion and he goes through
the abuse of discussion analysis and at
the end he says well but even if it's
denovo same result because even under
under a denovo review the lack of
objective evidence is an important
factor to consider it's not the only
Factor right but but still if if someone
has a claim and they have objective
proof of their disability that is a
stronger claim than someone who comes in
without it so if you don't is it a
stronger claim or is it just a different
claim I mean you know but one of the
things is a broken leg stronger than SK
phrenia well there there are ways to
diagnose
schizophrenia um and and some conditions
have some uh tests for them that sound a
little objective and a good example is
Fibromyalgia the test for fibromyalgia
is an 18o trigger test that's never been
done on Mrs cozy there are some cases
where they do the 18-point trigger test
yes they've got it it's somewhat
subjective as to whether it it prevents
them from working but but it's not a
situation where their claim is
permanently safe from any type of
outside analysis another example is
depression that the doctor looks at the
person and says they they look depressed
somewhat subjective but but at least
there's some corroboration there here we
have a case where that corroboration is
lacking um and and we we really also
don't even have a firm diagnosis we have
uh we have the term fibromyalgia used
but we have no formal fibromyalgia dosis
no treatment for fibromyalgia so how
could you find that she is disabled
under any standard but the plan doesn't
require a diagnosis it doesn't require
it but it's obviously something that
would be relevant to look at as part of
looking at all of the factors the courts
have said to course but it doesn't
require
it right right no it doesn't require
objective proof but I can I say that
that I it doesn't require objective
proof and it doesn't require a diagnosis
it requires proof of disability right
and it's difficult to do that in this
case where she's got no objective proof
no
diagnosis client drafted the plan
correct so what are we supposed to do
with that well you still have client
could have required all of that didn't
and now you come into court arguing well
there's no diagnosis there's no
objective evidence there's no requir
there's no requirement in the plan that
any of that be there well there is a
requirement that that she meet the
definition of disability under this plan
that she'd be dis disabled that she be
disabled and and what I'm trying to
argue here is the medical records just
don't support that she is disabled and
she cannot meet her burden of proof as a
plain if to prove that she's disabled um
and and fibromyalgia is not the only
issue to talk about but you know when
she's not treating for it at all that is
much different than other cases that
have said well we know that there's no
objective proof but the person's still
treating for this and the doctors say
that they they have it this is a
situation where if she has um uh
fibromyalgia it is reasonable to ask why
did you not follow the doctor's advice
to see a ologist why are you not
treating for it and if it's truly
disabling where is the evidence that
that the the
fibromyalgia is is disabling it's just
not in the record another issue to
discuss that might be a question the
judge could ask at a
trial if there doesn't get to ask that
on summary judgment well but we would be
at trial limited to the the record
anyway and there's no more evidence no
more medical evidence than that's going
to come in other than what but you're
relying on her failure to do a b and c
and that's not in the
record right you do those things I
understand the understand as the
administrator you can rely
on what's not in the record but once it
comes to court it seems to
me well if you draw inferences in favor
of the claimant under a denovo standard
in the face of a plan that doesn't
require diagnosis doesn't require
objective evidence
and in light of the fact that you could
have had her examined for example by a
rheumatoid specialist you chose not to
which is your right there's no legal
requirement that you do so these are the
kinds of considerations arguably I'm
look I'm just trying to explore this
with you the judge maybe shouldn't Grant
some re judgment well under a denovo
standard even in a denovo standard the
default rule is that you're still
limited to the administrative record
there is some case law that says you can
go outside that in special circumstance
ances but I would submit a trial would
be of limited utility if we're we're
looking at the administrative record and
and the absence of proof that's in the
record now is still going to be an
absence of proof but there may be an
explanation for the absence of proof we
haven't heard that we haven't heard that
in the briefing or um the the argument
so far I'm not sure it would it would
show up in the briefing it would show up
I mean she would have to explain why she
didn't have this test or that test or
this examination or that
examination which that be well she she
also had every opportunity to do that
during the administrative process she
could have said letters she did send a
lengthy statement she could have
included in there I uh I I'm choosing
not to follow the advice of my doctor to
follow up with a rheumatologist for XYZ
reason um we do have uh an argument I
Believe In The Briefing that she
couldn't afford but she saw other
doctors sub she couldn't afford it well
she has seen why did she see other
doctors subsequent to that um and the
record does not support that that's an
argument uh she lives on a golf course
community in in South Carolina and the
record just doesn't support that she
doesn't have enough money to see a
rumatologist but there is evidence in
the record that she doesn't think that
that that she has um fibromyalgia and
that she thinks that the fatigue is the
result of enderal which is a beta
blocker she's adjusted the dosage you'll
recall that she moved from North
Carolina to South Carolina in about mid2
2008 and started seeing a new um uh
primary care physician down there and
those records if you read through them
uh she she's reporting only only mild
fatigue during this important time
period and uh she her theory about
what's going on is that the enderal that
she takes for her Tremors is too high of
a dose and she needs to be on a lower
dose in in order to uh help with her
fatigue interal is a beta blocker it's
widely prescribed it does have a mild
sedating effect there's no evidence in
record that the enderal uh had such a
sedating effect that it prohibited her
from work and in the last uh record that
we have um from Dr Miller this is the
second Dr Miller uh seems to indicate
that when they reduce the enderal dosage
that her fatigue um improved so we have
not just an objective uh medical case we
have a case where there's a question as
to diagnosis uh there's no objective
medical and there there also uh very
weak statements of support from her
treating Physicians she's treated with
as the district court noted upwards of
15 doctors um her her current primary
care physician does not say that she's
disabled the primary care physician she
was seeing in South Carolina believes
that she's disabled but if you read that
letter it really is just a a
regurgitation of Miss Cozy's symptoms
there's no analysis of of what
specifically she can't do she just
recites the symptoms and says that that
adds up to a disability but if you look
through the symptoms you'll see that she
says things that that are uh
contradicted by the Specialists that
were referred to for example she says
that uh she's disabled because she can't
stay awake all day long she had
extensive sleep studies that that that
uh were unable to confirm why she would
have daytime sleepiness the
endocrinologist the cardiologist the
neurologist all found nothing wrong with
her another aspect of Dr Davis's letters
that she's forgetful
um well she uh was was referred by her
own doctors for a neuropsychological
exam and another examination by a
psychologist and they found nothing
wrong with her cognitively what they
found is is that she likely has a somata
form disorder where she she is um not
having a physical cause for her fatigue
but but stress is is is causing her a
mental issue where she thinks um that
she has these symptoms um was also
referred to go uh do uh psychological
talk therapy which she did not do um
there's been no neurological explanation
for her her alleged dizziness she does
have a Tremor but throughout the records
that's consistently described as mild at
one point she says she can live with it
uh the Tremor does increase somewhat
when the endall dosage goes down but
they seem to have found an appropriate
balance for that
um and
uh ultimately no matter what you think
about the standard of review the
plaintiff Bears the the burden of proof
in the case to show that she is is
disabled and and here we have a number
of factors that weigh against that
finding as we've talked about there's
the the lack of objective evidence but
there's also um medical records that
report mild symptoms I I've seen a
number of these cases where the
complaints are subjective but the person
is going to the doctor frequently
they're complaining of severe pain and
severe fatigue during 2009 when she was
V visiting with Dr Miller plaintiff
reported uh that her fatigue was on one
occasion one out of 10 another occasion
two out of 10 another occasion three out
of 10 um towards the end of the year she
reported that that it was improving um
as I mentioned she she has only
conclusory support from from some of her
trading Physicians not all she was able
to run her own business for apparently
up to a year after she uh became
disabled she moved to South Carolina in
uh mid2 2008 towards the end of the
summer she continued to work and the
plan was she was going to move back to
North Carolina um but she decided in
April that she was disabled again never
made the move back to North Carolina uh
her press release indicates that she'd
been making preparations um to run her
own coupon business and so when you add
all those factors together there just is
not enough evidence of the disability to
satisfy the plain's burden of proof even
even under a denovo standard on on the
the standard review there's probably not
much I can say that's different than
than what we've put um in the briefing
the issue is whether the language
satisfactory to credential is sufficient
for the long-term disability pieces some
courts have said it is some courts have
said it's not uh Gallagher took issue
with um the the phrase to us because it
was not clear whether the submission
goes there or what satisfactory has to
be to the ensure the language here is
different um and courts within district
courts within the fourth circuit have
been split on whether that that
difference is sufficient um and then on
the short-term piece the uh
administrative service agreement has uh
clear notice of the discretionary
language and it is incorporated by
reference into the the short-term plan
document so if the administrator has
discretion the review would be abuse of
discretion correct but if he doesn't
have any then it be denovo correct
that's the bottom line that's right that
is absolutely correct and is there any
contention as to whether or not he had
discretion in this case there is there
is plaintiff um says that that that the
satisfactory to credential language is
not sufficient defendants argue that it
is sufficient to invoke discretionary
review um and and and I see I have a few
minutes to to talk about the
pre-existing condition issue before I
get into that I I I do want to respond
um uh to comments that were made earlier
about what would a remand look like if
if we have a remand and I think that
that there the issues are different if
you're talking about a remand for
another look under a denovo review is
one thing and the pre-existing condition
is different and the reason I think it's
different is because the district court
did not address the pre-existing
condition there is some argument that
that you would have further development
uh when that comes back up if it does
come back up whereas the denovo thing I
think we would end up not in a different
situation and the judicial economy
argues in favor of of going ahead and
looking at it under denovo standard if
you get to that point so that we don't
have a situation where it goes back uh
the district judge says well I'd sort of
already said that this would be the same
under under the denovo standard and so
we have a similar order to what we have
now and then we have to come back on
appeal and it it it takes time and so
you're urging us if we decide that the
novo applies just go ahead and decide to
case after El uh except for the
pre-existing except for the pre-existing
good that's correct I
see
um I could just look at my note yeah I'm
sorry to so to to explain what the
pre-existing is um even knowing the
court may not reach the issue so what
the language says is that a medical
condition for which the claimant
receives treatment consultation care
services including diagnostic measures
or took medicine or followed uh
treatment recommended within 3 months
before the effect date that uh that it
that condition's excluded she was
re-employed on August 4th 2008 I I I
disagree with plaintiff's argument that
that she had continuous coverage because
the plan has an actively at work
requirement if you're not working 33
hours a week you're not covered and so
when she when her employment terminated
and she wasn't working she was eligible
to continue a disability if it was
established for the disability under the
plan
but once she left and came back you have
a new effective date a new 3mon period
and during that 3-month period She had
minimum had a June 25th 2008 visit with
Dr Davis um where she was seen for
balance problems her energy level and
the Tremor uh so your contention is that
a leave of absence terminates
coverage there is a definition for leave
of absence but what it says is that the
leave of absence has to be agreed to in
writing in advance by the employer so if
the employer says 'you need to be out
for 3 months okay here's we're going to
write that down you're out for three
months coverage doesn't end but if the
employment is terminated and there's no
Advance agreement in writing to come
back then then it doesn't continue it
terminates and when you're rehired you
start over is what the plan
documents and
finally and you want the district court
to look at that in the first sentence if
we send it back correct correct and uh
unless there are further questions I
thank the boort thank you very much Mr
De
Carlo you have just a few minutes Mr
Adams thank you honor I'll go quickly
because I have a couple of things I'd
like to respond to um first I wanted to
make one quick point on the long-term
disability standard review issue uh and
the reason is because the case came out
last month that I think has a lot of
bearing on that uh the case was called
I have it here
um gross versus sunlife and First
Circuit case uh yes yes your honor I
think it it does what I presented in the
to The District Court should be done um
in re relooking at the language I think
the fourth circuit is open as to what um
that language means and now the first 2
third seventh and Ninth have found that
doesn't give discretion and gross does a
very good job of going going outlining
all of that
um just to respond to a couple of points
um Mr n Carlo stated that the 18-point
trigger test has never been done on Miss
cozy I don't see the results in the
record but there are at least a half
dozen references to it having been done
in the record um Dr hes which is one of
their
reviewers on her review of the record
said quote primary care physician noted
tender points consistent with
fibromyalgia that's on a211 um in
credentials denial they referen her
diagnosed fibromyalgia that's on 1,000
that's all I could find in the lastes
but I know there are a number of other
places where it's referen as having been
done
um I would I would Echo the um I think
the court got to in terms of why she has
not followed up with as much Medical
Care as credential would like they took
away both her income and her medical
insurance at the same time um she does
uh live in Myrtle Beach she's also gone
through Chapter 7 bankruptcy I think
that's in the record to all since this
has happened um so I don't think it's a
a particularly reasonable to ask why she
hasn't gotten all this additional
Medical Care
um I I I may have Mard but I thought I
heard that uh some question as to the
reason why she can't travel um but I
wanted to note Dr Davis on page 493 her
former manager on 498 her former
supervisor on 175 and her declaration
herself on 83 through 88 all reference
her inability to fly um as opposed to
just maybe a lithium prescription or I
think I believe was referenced
um uh with respect to the pre-existing
condition I've got about a dozen
arguments in the brief that I'll rest on
except for the point of saying that and
I don't know if this throws another
procedural uh snag into the case but
that was never decided by presedential
until the final denial it wasn't decided
on an earlier denial and the gagano case
from the fourth circuit held that the
insurer violated 1133 by raising the
pre-existing condition exclusion as a
new basis for termination during the
final claim appeal in as much as it did
not give an opportunity to appeal the
decision because as it was a new basis
for denying it was also an initial
Denial on the pre-existing condition
issue so it may even
if this court doesn't decide it the
question would be whether it goes not to
the district court but also all the way
back down I see my time is up and I
thank you your honors thank you Mr Adams
and we thank both Council for your
presentations um we will uh ask the
clerk to adjuring court uh and stand in
recess come down and greet Council this
honorable Court stands journ sign a die
God save the United States and this
honorable Court